## Mikhail Rusakovich

Highly motivated person with 3 years experience in software development with broad experience in working with Java-based tools and frameworks on different platforms. Mostly experienced in developing of full stack enterprise- and web- applications. Also I always have a great passion for learning new technologies, algorithms and really enjoy all kinds of open-source stuff.

#### **Contacts:**

• Tel: +375 29 1798417

• Email: mikhail.complete@gmail.com

• Skype: mikhail.complete

• My legal name: Mikhail Rusakovich

### Skills

- Java, Groovy, C, PL/SQL (Oracle dialect, inc. some query optimization, hierarchical queries), JavaEE (JSF, EJB, JPA, Servlets, JSP, JAX-WS, JAX-RS, JNDI, JMS, CDI), JAXB, JCE, Spring, GWT, Hibernate, ActiveMQ, Apache CXF, JavaFX, Swing, Applets, JUnit, Mockito, Arquillian
- Object Oriented Analysis and Design, GOF-Patterns, Multithreading
- Web basic: HTTP, TCP/IP, HTML/CSS, Ajax, JavaScript, jQuery
- Application and web containers: Weblogic, JBoss (WildFly), Tomcat, Glassfish
- Specifications: XML, XSD, XSLT
- Tools: Jenkins CI, Sonatype Nexus, Jira, SoapUI, Wireshark, SVN, Git, Maven, Ant, NSIS installation system
- Strong knowledge: digital signature, security providers, CSP architecture, PKCS7 and CMS formats, certificates, CRL

# Work experience

• Java Developer, Sep 2012–Jul 2013, Dec 2014 - present

Developing and support TOPBY.by B2B EDI message provider which includes numerous conversion and connecting modules between customers located throughout the country.

Also taking part in architecture development.

- Company: SoftClub, Minsk, Belarus
- Responsibilities: Developing, testing, external system researching, profiling, debugging, reporting, integration with external systems
- Tools & technologies used: Java, C, JavaScript, JNI, Weblogic, Tomcat, Arquillian, ActiveMQ, Apache CXF, Spring, Groovy, JPA, JDBC, JAXB, XML, XSD, XSLT, Applets, JCE, Swing, JavaFX, Maven, SVN, Jira, Nexus, NSIS Scriptable Install System

#### What was made:

- installed application server's domain for high-load message processing;
- developed scalable message processing application based on a legacy code;
- deployed digital signature infrastructure, which includes supporting multiple security providers on the client and server side;
- integration with multiple partners using SOAP, REST, JMS;
- implemented numerous conversion modules from internal customer format to EANCOM and back;
- developed document generation system based on organization's templates;
- embedded SSF-security module for SAP system;
- introduced OAuth-authorization for mobile devices;

### • Java Developer, Jan 2014–Dec 2014

Homecredit Bank Belarus ibank retail. Internet banking for individuals.

- Company: SoftClub, Minsk, Belarus
- Responsibilities: Frontend and backend developing, debugging, bug fixing, testing, reporting
- Tools & technologies used: Java, JSF (ICEfaces), JSP, EJB, IFX Framework, Hibernate, Oracle, JasperReports, JBoss, Dozer, Ant, jQuery, prototype.js, SVN, Jira

#### What was made:

- designed prototype-based interface;
- written database mapping in conformity with database model;
- implemented business logic in accordance with the specification;
- developed document reporting system;
- integration with external services using SOAP, JMS;

## • Java Developer, Jul 2013–Jan 2014

BUTB.by Belarusian Universal Commodity Exchange. Exchange trading system.

- Company: SoftClub, Minsk, Belarus
- Responsibilities: Backend and service developing, testing, reporting, integration with external systems
- Tools & technologies used: Java, EJB, JPA, Servlets, Glassfish, Oracle PL/SQL, SOAP,
  Velocity, XDocReport, Groovy, Ant, SVN, Jira

#### What was made:

- trading services exposition via SOAP;
- implemented business logic in accordance with the specification;
- written scheduling tasks for back-end;
- developed scripts for batch processing;
- integration with customer's legacy software;

# Own open source projects

• https://bitbucket.org/mikhail\_complete/smarthome

SmartHouse project is an attempt to create a universal platform for the management of home devices using popular interface interaction. At the moment, you can work with devices on the serial, USB and 1-wire protocols, and survey your real estate using a large number of supported cameras. To add support for the device is quite easy - you just need to add it in one of the configuration files. Also, some kinds of mock-devices are available for development stage. For complex logic devices control a special expression language was developed

- Tools & technologies used: Java, C, GWT, Jetty, Spring, RMI, JNI, Bootstrap, JQuery,
  WebSocket, Maven, JUnit, Mockito, Cucumber, Selenium WebDriver, Git
- https://github.com/creepid/DocsReporter

Documents reporting system in docx, odt, pdf, xhtml and pptx formats extending XDocReport project and using Spring Framework. Supported template formats: .docx, .odt and .pptx

- Tools & technologies used: Java, Spring, Velocity, Freemarker, JUnit, Mockito, Maven, Git
- https://github.com/creepid/jusbrelay

Multiplatform Java library for USB relay control. Supported platforms: Windows, Linux, Apple OS X. Also Python (CPython) library is available for testing purposes.

- Tools & technologies used: Java, C, Python, JNI, JUnit, Maven, Git
- https://github.com/creepid/capicom-wrapper

Java wrapper for Microsoft capicom library

- Tools & technologies used: Java, Jacob, COM, CSP, JUnit, Maven, Git

## Education

• Belarusian State University, 2008–2013

Diploma in Researching Physics.

Degree work on a theme:

Development of software for EPR spectrometer management

# Foreign languages

## • English

Spoken, writing at an upper-intermediate level. Reading and understanding professional technical documentation.

# Appendix

- $\bullet \ \, \rm https://github.com/creepid$
- https://bitbucket.org/mikhail\_complete